# Wei Chen

626-A Broadmoor Dr, Chesterfield, MO, 63017, chen60@go.wustl.edu phone:314-583-5169

## **Summary**

Motivated, disciplined M.S. in Electrical Engineering candidate with technical manufacturing and business administration experience. Strong desire to contribute in a manufacturing, design or technical support function utilizing my experience and education. Willing to travel and relocate. Available January 2014.

# **Education**

#### **Washington University in St. Louis**

St. Louis, MO, Graduation Dec. 2013

- M.S. Electrical & Computer Engineering, Cumulative GPA: 3.70/4.0
- Relevant courses: Partial Differential Equation, Linear Dynamic System, Non-Linear Dynamic System, Transmission and Multiplexing, Medical Imaging Technology, Estimation and Detection Algorithm, Optimization Algorithm, Photonic Communication, Probability and Stochastic Process, Financial Mathematic.

# **University of Missouri-St. Louis**

St. Louis, MO, Graduation Dec. 2010

- B.S. Electrical Engineering, GPA: 3.58/4.0
- Graduated Magna Cum Laude

#### **Shanghai TV University**

Shanghai, China, Graduation Feb. 2002

Associate Degree of Science, Electrical Technology

#### **Fudan University**

Shanghai, China, Graduation July 1993

• Associate Degree of Science, Accounting

## **Work and Research Experience**

#### Washington University in St. Louis, Research Assistant

St. Louis, MO, Jan. 2012-May 2013

- Constructed ultrasound image through temperature distribution in order to improve resolution of image
- Applied estimation and detection algorithm to take noise off for Positron Emission Tomography (PET) imaging
- Optimized communication net structure

#### University of Missouri- St. Louis, Leader of project team

St. Louis, MO, Jan. 2010-Nov. 2010

- Digital Image Processing: Designed an algorithm to trace the boundary of multiple objects in a digital image, using MATLAB and then displaying the contour and speed
- Electrical and Magnetic Project: Designed single TE (Transverse Electric) mode unbalance slab wave guide

## Shanghai Fanshun Logistic Co, Ltd. Vice Manager

Shanghai, China, Jan. 1999-June 2007

- Expanded the business of equipment modification and trouble shooting
- Coordinated 20 sales representatives in five provinces
- Coordinated 15 engineers in local region and constructed the engineering process schedules
- Designed and developed switch circuit and product line monitor equipment

#### Shanghai Donghuan International Freight Co, Ltd. Sales Coordinator

Shanghai, China, Mar. 1996-Dec. 1998

- Doubled sales per representative from \$0.5 million to \$1 million.
- Coordinated 120 sales representatives in five provinces.
- Implemented a training course for new recruits speeding profitability.

# Shanghai Zhongtai International Freight Co, Ltd. Junior Accountant

Shanghai, China, Aug. 1994-Feb. 1996

- Served as junior accountant
- Helped sales department to predict costs and profits.

# **Skills and Interests**

Language: Chinese (Mandarin and Shanghai dialect, native), English (fluent)

Computer: C++, MATLAB, LabVIEW, Maple, Microsoft Office,